One Hundred Years of Women at UConn Collection
© 2002 University of Connecticut
One Hundred Years of Women at UConn Collection.
1991-1992.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
University of Connecticut. One Hundred Years of Women at UConn Committee.
2.5 linear feet.
The 1991-1992 academic year at UConn marked the 100th anniversary of women on the Storrs campus. The anniversary was celebrated by a year-long series of programs to commemorate the achievements of women, particularly those at the University of Connecticut.
MSS19930060
History
In 1991, President Harry J. Hartley appointed a committee to advise him on appropriate and necessary considerations for the celebration of the anniversary of the enrollment of women at the institution that would become the University of Connecticut. The committee of fifteen women, chaired by Professor Cynthia Adams, developed a year-long program of activities to meet the stated goals of the committee: To seek women of the highest caliber to honor; promote diversity of women throughout higher education; celebrate the achievements of women, particularly those at the University of Connecticut; recognize the historical path of women; identify and address those paths not yet taken by women at the University; and to advance the institutional value and role of women at UConn.
The activities included a convocation, lectures, presentations, awards and an exhibition on the Concourse between the Legislative Office Building and the State Capitol in Hartford during March 1992.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of the contents of a scrapbook created by the Committee to document the "100 Years" activities during the 1991-1992 academic year. The scrapbook contained photographs, clippings, programs, announcements, memoranda, correspondence, flyers, brochures and posters. The original scrapbook pages were photocopied in order prior to being disassembled and placed in folders. In addition, other materials in the University Archives associated with the project have been included in the collection, including the lists of captions for the photographs included in the exhibition and photocopies of the images. The original photographs have been reintegrated into the University Photograph Collection.
The original scrapbook, a flower print cloth bound, "magnetic" photograph album was returned to Professor Adams.
Organization
The collection has been arranged into three series, consistent with provenance:
Series I: Scrapbook (undated, 1991-1992) contains the contents of the original scrapbook as well as a photocopy of the scrapbook as it was originally ordered.
Series II: Exhibition Materials (undated, 1991-1992) includes descriptions and labels for the items included in the exhibition. Original photographs and negatives have been returned to the appropriate location in the University Photograph Collection.
Series III: Committee Files (undated, 1991-1992) contains memoranda, notes, drafts and other working materials associated with the activities of the project.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Places:
Storrs (Conn.)
Subjects:
Women--Education (Higher)--United States.; Women--Education (Higher)--Connecticut.; Education, Higher--United States--Social aspects.; Women college students--United States--Attitudes.; Wiomen--United States--History.
Document Types:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The scrapbook was donated to the University Archives in 2002. The exhibition materials are from the University Photograph Collection and the related descriptions and lists were created by the Historical Manuscripts and Archives Division of the University Libraries, a unit that is now part of Archives & Special Collections at the Dodd Center.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Scrapbook, undated, 1991-1992
  - Advertisements, invitations, administrative information, undated, 1991-1992 (Box 1:1)
  - Photographs, 1991-1992 (Box 1:2)
  - Letters, thank you cards, 1991-1992 (Box 1:3)
  - Newspaper articles and clippings, 1991-1992 (Box 1:4-5)
  - Photocopy of scrapbook in original order, 1991-1992 (Box 1:6)
- Series II: Exhibition materials, undated, 1991-1992
  - Exhibition materials, undated, 1991-1992 (Box 1:7)
- Series III: Committee Files, undated, 1991-1992
  - Aqua Turf Club, undated, 1991 (Box 1:8)
  - Banquet solicitations, undated, 1992 (Box 1:9-10)
  - Committee Files,undated, 1991-1992 (Box 1:11)
  - Committee Files, undated 1991-1992 (Box 2:12-13)
  - Correspondence, undated, 1992 (Box 3:13)
  - News articles and clippings, 1991-1992 (Box 3:14-15)
  - Upcoming meetings, 1991-1992 (Box 3:16)
  - Three t-shirts, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Oversize print materials, 1992 (Box 4)